《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
我们盯上你了  斯特兰奇教授
We're onto you, Professor Strange.
坏蛋进  怪物出
Bad guys come in. Monsters come out.
我是萤火虫
I am Firefly.
塞琳娜
Selina.
雨果·斯特兰奇抓走了塞琳娜
Hugo Strange has Selina.
记得你的名字吗
Do you remember your name?
我叫菲什·穆尼
My name is Fish Mooney.
给我做个烤奶酪三明治
Make me a grilled cheese sandwich.
你给我做了个三明治
You made me a sandwich.
-为什么  -我不知道
- Why? - I don't know.
那你究竟打算怎么进阿卡姆呢
And how exactly do you plan on getting into Arkham?
我要求去参观一下
I'll ask for a tour.
去找那个派人刺杀你父亲的人吗
From the man that ordered the assassination of your father?
他会想知道我们了解多少
He'll want to find out what we know.
他不会把我和卢修斯当成威胁
And he won't see me and Lucius as a threat.
我通知布洛克  他带一帮警察冲进去
I call Bullock, he comes busting in with a hundred cops.
抓住他们
Take them.
尽可能将一切都转移到州北的设施去
Move everything you can to the facility upstate.
你有爆炸装置  好好使用
You have an explosive device, use it.
毁掉印第安山
Destroy Indian Hill.
巴兹尔可以说是变色龙
Basil is a chameleon of sorts.
想见识一下吗
Would you like to see?
你个混蛋
You son of a bitch!
我是吉姆·戈登
I'm Jim Gordon.
好了  去救我们的哥们
Right, go get our guys.
没有戈登的踪迹
No sign of Gordon.
你要我们等多久
How long do you want us to wait?
再等他十秒
Give him ten seconds.
如果你们没看见吉姆  就炸开门进去找他
If you don't see Jim, bust that joint open and find him.
突击小队准备  数到一行动
Ready, entry team. We go on one.
上  掩护我
Go. Cover me.
上  上
Go! Go!
四  三
Four, three,
二...
two...
解除戒备
Stand down!
解除戒备  警员
Stand down, officers.
别开火
Hold! Hold!
解除戒备
Stand down.
-安全了  -解除戒备
- All clear. - Stand down! Stand down!
安全了吗
"All clear"?
很抱歉浪费了你的时间  伙计
Sorry to waste your time, hoss.
可以送我去总部吗
How about a ride to HQ?
当然  吉姆
Sure thing, Jim.
你还好吗
You okay?
你看着有点不对劲
You look kind of hinky.
我好极了
Never better.
仅供学习  禁止商用  更多影视
登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
斯特兰奇  斯特兰奇
Strange! Strange!
翻译 小胖纸Amy   辰星晓Reginamoon   Silence   DustD
斯特兰奇
Strange!
斯特兰奇  你个混蛋
Strange, you son of a bitch!
回来
Come back here!
翻译 charcie   大K   草草   后期 饿得慌
时间轴 风吹来的那片云   校对&总监 草草
看来...
So...
你真打算这么做喽
you're really doing this?
我说了不算
Not my call.
准备将病人转移到州北的设施去
Prepare the patients for transport to the upstate facility.
毁灭程序就绪
-你的病人哪怕逃了一个  -他们不会的
- If even one of your patients were to escape-- - They won't.
警方不会再逗留了
The police won't be delayed much longer.
准备转移  动作快点
Prepare the patients and move fast.
解决了戈登和韦恩后
As soon as we're done with Gordon and Wayne,
我们就引爆炸弹
we will detonate the bomb.
遵命  先生
Yes, sir.
毁灭程序就绪
哥谭
第二季  第二十二集
好了
Okay...
小神童们
quiz kids,
谁准备好玩
who's ready to play
生死游戏了
Life or Death?
尼格玛先生
Sir, Mr. Nygma.
你是尼格玛  对吗
You are Nygma, aren't you?
这太荒谬了
This is absurd.
警方知道我们在这里  你不能杀了我们
The police know we're here. You can't kill us!
你们准备好玩游戏了吗
Are you ready to play?!
准备好了
Yes.
很好
Good.
你们可以猜一次
You have one guess.
五分钟讨论时间
Five minutes to talk it over.
谁掌管了印第安山
Who runs Indian Hill?
你们可以猜一次
You have one guess.
仔细想想  伙计们
Think carefully, fellas.
得给出正确回答
Answer correctly...
不然就得死
or die.
斯特兰奇
Strange!
Strange?
那是什么
What is that?
吐真剂
Honesty serum.
我需要知道你都知道什么
I need to know what you know.
等等
Wait.
Wait!
你现在感觉如何
So, how do you feel now?
不好
Not good.
能说得更详细点吗
Can you be more specific?
我觉得很脆弱
I feel vulnerable.
无遮无掩
Naked.
这种感觉是完全自然且正常的
Your feelings are entirely natural and normal.
没必要觉得羞耻
There is nothing to be ashamed of.
你现在很无助
You are in a helpless situation.
你无计可施
There is nothing you can do.
明白了吗
Do you understand that?
明白了
Yes.
不
No.
No?
你还能做什么
What can you do?
詹姆斯  你还能做什么
James, what can you do?
我有个计划
Made a plan.
告诉我你的计划
Tell me your plan.
假如中午前我不和哥谭市警局联系
If I don't check in with the GCPD by noon,
向他们报平安的话
tell them I'm safe,
他们就会来抓你
they'll come after you.
没错
Yes.
没错  我知道
Yes, I know.
你已经和哥谭市警局联系上了
You did check in with the GCPD.
没有人会来了
Nobody's coming.
你可以放心了
You can relax.
吉姆
Jim?
哈维
Harv.
斯特兰奇没问题
Strange is clean?
怎么回事
What the hell happened?
死胡同
Dead end.
"死胡同"
"Dead end"?
你在说什么呢  "死胡同"
What are you talking about, "dead end"?
他有后台
He's connected.
我的机修工也有   谁没有呢
So is my mechanic. Who isn't?
他的后台我们惹不起
Connected to people we can't cross.
什么人
What people?
你不会想知道的
You don't want to know.
相信我
Trust me.
你还好吗
You feeling all right?
你看起来不太好
You look like a sack of fish.
也许是有点感冒了
A little flu, maybe.
好吧  那你离我远点
Oh. Well, then keep your distance.
我周末要约炮  祝我好运
I'm getting laid this weekend, fingers crossed.
你还剩60秒
You have 60 seconds left.
谁掌管了印第安山
Who runs Indian Hill?
我认为是雨果·斯特兰奇
I say Hugo Strange.
是韦恩集团
Wayne Enterprises.
是韦恩集团掌管了印第安山
Wayne Enterprises runs Indian Hill.
这只是猜测
That's surmise.
如果答案那么明显  他又何必问
Why would he ask that question if the answer was obvious?
他想知道我们都知道什么
He wants to know what we know.
我们以为自己知道什么
What we think we know.
就是韦恩集团
Which is wayne Enterprises.
这是你们的答案吗  时间要到了
Is that your answer? Running out of time here.
是的
Yes.
正确
Correct!
韦恩集团掌管了印第安山
Wayne Enterprises runs Indian Hill.
好极了  布鲁斯
Bravo, Brucie.
你就快安全了
You're almost safe.
还有一个问题
Just one more question.
-准备好了吗  -好了
- You ready? - Yes.
你有五分钟的时间  小神童
You have five minutes, quiz kids.
回答不正确就等死吧
Answer correctly or die.
韦恩集团掌管了印第安山
Wayne Enterprises runs Indian Hill,
但谁掌管了韦恩集团呢
but who runs Wayne Enterprises?
按照安全级别转移他们
Move 'em out in order of security grades.
低风险优先转移
Lowest risk first.
麻醉他们  让他们无法乱动  再转移到车上
Tranq 'em, immobilize them, and put them on the bus.
动作快点  但是要千万小心
And do it fast but very, very carefully.
安全是我们的首要考虑
Security is our number one priority.
遵命  女士
Yes, ma'am.
女士
Hey, lady.
忙着呢
Busy day, busy day.
会轮到你的  13号
We'll get to you, Number 13.
你妈妈也许是13号
Your mama may be Number 13,
但我是个人
but I'm a human being.
我是菲什·穆尼  贱人
Fish Mooney, bitch.
在这里  你只是复活实验13号病人
Here you're Re-Animant Test Case Number 13,
而我是皮博迪女士
and I'm Ms. Peabody.
你最好别提我妈妈
And you'd best not talk about my mama.
皮博迪女士
Ms. Peabody,
抱歉
I apologize.
我有点紧张
I'm a bit stressed.
我不喜欢被人关着
I don't like being locked up.
这有违我的本性
It's against my nature.
我明白
I understand. I do.
但你是极其重要的科学奇迹
But you are a priceless scientific miracle.
你就是历史
You are history.
禁闭着实令人遗憾
Seclusion is regrettable
但却无法避免
but inevitable.
我经历过这种事
Look, I've been here before.
你们这些疯狂科学家都是同一套说辞
All you mad scientists say the same kind of stuff.
我不在乎
I don't care.
放我出去
Let me go.
抱歉  13号
Sorry, 13.
我们走
Let's go.
你惹错人了
You're messing with the wrong woman!
听到没
You hear me?
惹错人了
The wrong woman!
这里怎么样
Here?
也许有点太正中央了
A little too central, maybe.
不能让一件摆设抢了整间屋子的风头
You don't want one piece to overpower the room.
放那边试试
Try over there.
你说得太对了
You're absolutely right.
看  我就说她肯定有用
See? I told you she'd be useful.
是不是好点了
Isn't that better?
室内装潢不是我的长项
Interior design ain't my thing.
哥谭无线电报整点新闻
News on the hour with WTGC.
警方消息称关于即将突袭
Police sources say that reports of an impending raid
阿卡姆疯人院  并逮捕其备受争议的院长
on Arkham Insane Asylum and its controversial chief,
雨果·斯特兰奇教授的报道是错误的
Professor Hugo Strange, are inaccurate.
虽然发布了声明
Despite the disclaimers,
警方在焦点设施周围的行动
flurries of police activity around the troubled facility
-让逮捕即将来临的谣言四起  -雨果
- have fueled rumors that arrests are imminent... - Hugo
斯特兰奇
Strange.
太有趣了
How interesting.
请快速回答  吉姆
Answer quickly, please, Jim.
不要思考
Without thinking.
你更爱谁  你母亲还是你父亲
Who did you love more, your mother or your father?
-母亲  -为什么
- Mother. - Why?
我讨厌我父亲的强势
I resented my father's strength.
懂了  好的
I see. Yes.
他死的时候
And when he died...
嗯
Yes.
你有什么感觉
...how did you feel?
愧疚
Guilty.
为了一场车祸  为什么
For a car crash? Why?
那不是你的错
It was not your fault.
我想象他死  然后他就死了
I imagined he was gone. And then he was.
你最近失去了一个孩子
You lost a child recently.
是的
Yes.
这又让你有何感觉
How does that make you feel?
愧疚
Guilty.
又是愧疚
Guilt again.
你怪罪你自己吗
You blame yourself?
那是我的错
It was my fault.
我懂了  我之前不知道
Oh. Oh, I see. I didn't know that.
孩子母亲怎么样了
And what happened to the mother?
-小莱  是吧  -她在
- Lee, was it? - She's...
南方的某个地方
down south somewhere.
你还爱她吗
You still love her?
是的
Yes.
你想和她在一起吗
You want to be with her?
是的
Yes.
为什么你没和她在一起呢
Why aren't you with her?
我让她遭受了太多痛苦
I've put her through enough pain.
吉姆  我需要你放松
Jim, I need you to relax.
闭上你的眼睛
Close your eyes.
把我想象成上帝
Imagine that I am God.
无所不能
All-powerful.
我是上帝
I am God,
我宽恕了你
and I absolve you
免去了你所有的罪
of all of your guilt.
我给了你那些罪过
I put that guilt on you,
现在
and now...
我将它们拿走了
I take it away.
消失了
It's gone.
你的负担消失了
Your burdens are gone.
感觉如何
So how do you feel?
不错
Good.
好多了
Better.
好
Good.
很好
Good, good.
吉姆
Jim...
既然你已放松下来
now that we're relaxed
也能坦言相告了  那说说
and speaking honestly, tell me:
关于我们在印第安山的工作  你知道些什么
what do you know about our work here at Indian Hill?
你们在为军事用途制造怪物
You're building monsters for military use.
我们的工作不仅如此  不过是为谁工作呢
Oh, we're doing much more than that, but for who?
印第安山归谁所有
Who owns Indian Hill?
韦恩集团
Wayne Enterprises.
谁在幕后控制韦恩集团
And who controls Wayne Enterprises behind the scenes?
谁在幕后
Who controls everything in Gotham...
控制哥谭的一切
behind the scenes?
我不知道
I don't know.
富人吗
The rich?
他们的确有钱
Oh, they are rich, I'm sure.
但你能说得具体些吗
But can you be more specific?
谁控制哥谭  吉姆
Who controls Gotham, Jim?
你从没听说过有个
You've never heard of a...
秘密议会吗
...secret council?
秘密议会
Secret council?
没有
No.
棒极了
Excellent.
谢谢
Thank you.
我就需要知道这个
That's what I needed to know.
斯特兰奇教授
Professor Strange?
什么事  吉姆
Yes, Jim?
你提到小莱
What you said about Lee.
我应该去找她吗
I should have gone after her.
毫无疑问
Oh, no doubt.
愧疚感迫使你为了良心牺牲真情
Guilt has compelled you to sacrifice your heart to your conscience.
但愧疚毫无用处
But guilt is useless.
爱  吉姆
Love, Jim.
爱为我们指引前路
Love is our guide.
时间到了
Time's up, I'm afraid.
本着亲密与诚实的精神
In the spirit of intimacy and honesty,
我跟你聊你的人生
I have been speaking about your life
就好像你还有未来似的
as if it had a future.
然而
And...
事实却非如此
that is not so.
你还剩几个小时
You have a few hours.
你们还剩30秒
You have : 30 seconds left.
谁掌管了韦恩集团
Who runs Wayne Enterprises?
也许是魔鬼  是这意思吗
Oh, the devil, maybe. Is that the deal?
共产党  女巫吗
Communists? Witches?
不  这问题后一定有真相
No. There's some truth behind this question.
有个大秘密
Some big secret.
我为韦恩集团工作了十年
I've worked for Wayne Enterprises for ten years--
没有什么大秘密
there is no big secret.
董事会掌管韦恩集团
The board of directors runs Wayne Enterprises.
15秒了
15 seconds.
那不可能是答案  卢修斯
That can't be the answer, Lucius.
10秒了
Ten seconds.
再给我们些时间
Give us more time!
5秒了
Five seconds!
董事会
The board of directors.
不正确
Incorrect.
真可惜啊
Oh, what a shame.
正确答案是
The correct answer is...
抱歉  两位  你们输了
Sorry, fellas. You lose.
输的人会怎么样呢
And what happens to losers?
被毒气毒死
Death by poison gas!
吉姆
Jim.
我们还活着吗
Are we alive?
目前还活着
So far, so good.
得确定一下  我以为我们死了
Had to be sure-- I thought we were dead.
刚才真不舒服啊
Wow, that was unpleasant.
你这边怎么样
How are things going for you?
我们刚才特别惨
We've had a hell of a time.
一样
The same.
你没事吧
You okay?
我有些晕
I'm a little groggy.
他给我下药了
He drugged me.
逼我开口
Made me talk.
询问韦恩集团的事吧
About Wayne Enterprises, right?
问了所有事
About everything.
布鲁斯
Bruce...
我就不该跟你立誓
I never should have made that oath to you.
-那不是...  -我太自大太天真了
- That's not really... - I was arrogant and naive...
我很抱歉
and I'm sorry.
我想做正确的事  但
I've tried to do the right thing, but...
我太傻了
what a fool I've been.
他们给你下了什么药
What kind of drugs did they give you?
干得漂亮  爱德  很厉害
Well done, Ed. I'm impressed.
你有点像巫师啊
You are a shaman of sorts.
-巫医  -悄悄告诉我
- A witch doctor. - So, just between us,
是谁掌管着韦恩集团
who does run Wayne Enterprises?
我可以告诉你  但那样
I could tell you, but then...
我就得切断你的脑叶了
I would have to lobotomize you.
懂了
Gotcha.
接下来  先生  我很乐意
So, moving forward, sir, I would be more than happy
在其它病例中协助你
to help you with any of your other cases.
你本会是个很得力的员工  爱德
You would be a wonderful addition to my staff, Ed,
得力助手  前提是你精神正常
a wonderful addition, if you were only sane.
-不  说真的  -是说真的
- No, seriously... - Yes, seriously.
你帮了大忙  我们这些自大的医生
You have been very useful, and we arrogant physicians
有很多要像你这样的疯子学习
have much to learn from a madman like you.
但没那么多
But not that much.
不不不不
No! No, no, no, no!
你不能把我当疯子对待
You will not treat me like a crazy person!
不
No!
夫人  我带来了好消息
Madam, I bring good news.
戈登  韦恩和福克斯并不知道任何重要的事
Gordon and Wayne and Fox know nothing but mundanities.
他们也没把真相告诉任何人
They have told no one the truth,
因为他们并不知道真相
because they have none of the truth.
我们的秘密很安全
Our secret is safe.
杀了他们
Kill them all,
然后继续撤离实验对象
then continue with the evacuation of your test subjects.
是  夫人
Yes, madam.
印第安山的摧毁按原计划进行
The destruction of Indian Hill may proceed as scheduled.
释放盖勒文是你的大失误
Releasing Galavan was a grave error on your part.
你的病人无论如何绝不能
No more of your patients will see the light of day
再有一个
under any circumstances,
被放出去
at any cost.
我明白  夫人
I understand, madam.
斯特兰奇的后台
These people to whom Strange is connected,
他们肯定很厉害吧  你才会肯放弃
they must be pretty heavy, huh, to make you back off.
是啊  非常厉害
Oh, they're heavy.
我不想招惹危险
I don't want anything dangerous..
我只是喜欢刺激
I just like being titillated.
说真的  你不会想知道的
Seriously, you don't wanna know.
记得那次你从医院打给我
Remember the time you called me from the hospital
你用轮床推着法尔科内
when you had Falcone on the gurney,
整个城市的人都在找你  想杀了你俩
and the whole town and their uncle were looking to kill you both?
怎么忘得了呢
How could I forget?
记得我在电话上跟你说了什么吗
Remember what I said to you on the phone?
记得我怎么说的吗
Remember what I said?
忘记了
I forget.
真有意思
That's funny.
戈登  你回来了  怎么回事
Gordon, you're back. What happened?
布鲁斯少爷呢  卢修斯呢
Where's Master Bruce? Where's Lucius?
他们在哪  你见到他们了吗
Where are they?! Have you seen them?
阿尔弗雷德  别激动
Hey, Alfred, take it easy.
-他们在哪  -阿尔弗雷德
- Where are they? - Alfred... Alfred...
放松
relax.
布鲁斯少爷和卢修斯
Master Bruce and Lucius are, uh,
回韦恩庄园了
headed back to Wayne Manor.
你净胡扯
Yeah, well, that's a load of hot tosh for starters, isn't it?
-我刚从那儿来  -我怎么知道
- I've just come back from there. - What can I tell ya?
或许他们路上去买吃的了
Maybe they... stopped to get a snack.
那斯特兰奇呢
So, what about Strange?
很复杂
It's complicated.
说啊  怎么回事
Well, go on, then! What?!
这是复杂的警方事务
Complicated police business!
他得流感了
He's got a touch of the flu.
你
You.
你怎么样了
How you doing?
挺好  你怎么样
Middling. What's your deal?
挺好
Chillin'.
他们要把这里炸飞
They're gonna blow this dump sky-high
所有人都要转移去州北
and the whole circus is moving upstate.
什么时候
When?
马上了  一小时后
Soon. Like, an hour.
-你能逃掉吗  -当然
- Can you escape? - 'Course.
萤火虫把我当小弟  我获得了他们的信任
Firefly thinks I'm her sidekick, so I got trusty status.
那就跑吧  离开这里  然后去报警
Then please do so. Get out of here and call the police.
我想干什么干什么
I'll do what I like.
是我把你扯了进来  我太自以为是
I led you into this mess-- I was self-righteous
自大  我操纵了你
and arrogant and manipulative.
我利用了你  我很抱歉
I used you, and I'm sorry.
你还有那本事吗
Like you can use me.
是我把你治得服服帖帖差不多
I got you wrapped around my pinky.
一向如此
Always have.
尽管如此
Be that as it may...
如果你能逃  就逃吧
if you can escape, do it.
操纵我
Manipulative.
才见鬼呢
As if.
她怎么说的
What'd she say?
她想干什么干什么
She'll do what she likes.
而且有颗炸弹
And there's a bomb.
你好  13号
Hello, number 13.
镇静
Stay calm.
没人会伤害你的
No one's going to hurt you.
该出去走走了
It's time to go on a trip.
把你的右臂伸出来
Give me your right arm.
说我的名字
Say my name.
菲什·穆尼
Fish Mooney.
没错
That's right.
你叫什么
What's your name?
埃塞尔·皮博迪
Ethel Peabody.
埃塞尔
Ethel...
你好像很难过
you seem sad
还焦虑
and anxious.
-没错  -放我出去
- You got that right. - You let me out of here...
我就是你的朋友
and I'll be your friend.
不不不
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
有意思  皮博迪女士
Interesting. Ms. Peabody,
你在做什么
what are you doing?
照她说的做
What she says.
为什么
Why?
我不知道
I don't know.
穆尼女士
Miss Mooney,
你有特别的才能
you have special talents.
你皮肤上有某种精神控制化学物质吧
Some form of psychotropic chemical agent on your skin, I imagine.
你真是神奇
You're marvelous.
太神奇了
Yes, truly marvelous.
一向如此
Always was.
没错
Indeed.
我很想好好聊聊我  但我们还得赶大巴呢
Would love to chat about me, but we have a bus to catch.
不  穆尼女士
No, Miss Mooney,
如果你和大巴上的其他人出去露面
if you and the others on that bus were to appear in public,
会掀起革命  引发天启
it would cause a revolution, an apocalypse.
我实在不能允许你就这么走出去
I simply can't allow you to just walk out of here.
瞧我的
Watch me.
求你  别走
Oh, please, don't go.
求你  你这要伤我的心的
Please, you're breaking my heart.
我像爱亲生女儿一样爱你
I love you like my own daughter.
没人会比我更爱你
No one could love you more,
但我宁可杀了你  也不会放你走
but I will have to kill you before I let you go.
求你  选择生命吧
Please, choose life.
你当皮条客肯定很厉害
You would have made a great pimp.
不不不
No, no, no, no.
不不
No, no, no!
把他抓回来
Bring him back.
毁灭程序就绪
雨果
Hugo...
我命令你停手
I order you to stop...
马上
now.
毁灭程序就绪
住手
Stop...
快住手
now!
听到了吗
You hear me?
毁灭程序就绪
就绪
安全系统启动
Security systems activated.
不
No!
打过几千通电话了
Tried calling about a thousand times.
还是没人接
Still no answer.
斯特兰奇一定是抓走了他
Strange has him, I'm positive.
老天爷
Holy crap,
你怎么还在  我都说了
are you still here? I told you a thousand times
斯特兰奇没问题
Strange is clean.
他归你负责  是吧
You in charge of that, are you?
不过好奇怪啊
It's strange, though, isn't it?
他们失踪了  这好奇怪
I mean, strange they're MIA.
真逗
Ha, that's funny.
-奇怪  -逗
- Strange. - Funny?
或许我该派突击队再去一趟阿卡姆
You know, maybe I should send the strike force back into Arkham,
-让他们去瞧瞧  -不不
- have a little look see. - No, no, no.
别那么做
You don't want to do that.
坏主意  相信我
Bad idea. Trust me.
这主意糟透了
That's a terrible idea.
你认识我多久了
How long you known me?
好吧
All right,
如果你觉得没问题  我也没问题
if you're good, I guess I'm good.
我不知道是谁把你怎么了  戈登  但你
I don't know who's got to you, Gordon, but you're just, just...
太奇怪了
...weird.
阿尔弗雷德
Hey, Alfred.
基恩小姐
Miss Kean.
管家行业近来如何
How's the butling business?
何事大驾...
To what do we owe the...
吉米  我的爱
Jimmy, my love,
你肯定很忙
I'm sure you're ever so busy,
但我们能单独谈谈吗
but could we have a word in private?
当然
You bet.
你真不成样子
Well, you look terrible.
谢谢了  芭芭拉  你美极了
Gee, thanks, Barbara. You look pretty good.
得了
Shucks.
问个问题  阿卡姆究竟怎么回事
Question, what the hell is going on down at Arkham?
回问你两个问题  美女
Two questions back at you, gorgeous.
你为什么问这个  我有什么好处
Why you asking, and, uh, what's in it for me?
我问是因为我一个好朋友
I'm asking because a dear friend of mine
想知道答案
wants to know the answer,
你希望得到什么好处
and what would you like to be in it for you?
春天来了  亲爱的
Hey, spring is here, baby.
你又喜欢我了吗
So, now you like me again?
有什么好不喜欢的
What's not to like?
你忘记小莱了吗
So, you've forgotten about Lee.
小莱
Lee?
小莱·汤普金斯
Lee Thompkins.
去那个娘们
Nah, screw that ho.
都是过去了
Water under the bridge.
你不是吉姆
You're not Jim.
什么
Say what now?
你不是吉姆
You're not Jim!
等等  妹子
Hold on there, woman.
老天爷
Holy mother of saints.
杀了所有囚犯  我们得走了
Kill the captives. We have to go.
我们去哪  急什么
Where are we going? What's the hurry?
闭嘴
Silence.
弗莱斯  赶紧的
Freeze, get it done.
天呐  放松
Jeez, relax.
他怎么回事
What's with him?
闭嘴
Quiet!
你闭嘴
Quiet yourself.
你为什么非要杀了他们
Why do you have to kill them?
你为什么这么坏
Why are you so mean?
我就知道不该饶了你
I knew I shouldn't have spared you.
弗莱斯  杀了她
Freeze, kill her.
等等
Wait a minute!
对不起  萤火虫
I'm sorry, Firefly.
我说了  她只是个实验
I told you she was an experiment.
但她是我的朋友  我需要她
But she's my friend. I need her.
我们没时间争了
We don't have time for this.
别让他伤害我
Please, don't let him hurt me.
萤火虫
Firefly...
帮帮我吧
...please, help me.
你敢
Don't you dare.
闪开  小火花
Out of the way, sparky.
逼我啊
Make me.
萤火虫  别
Firefly, no.
别
No!
又怎么了
What now?
听上去是打起来了
Sounds like warfare.
怎么回事
What's going on?
心理学
Simple psychology.
一直在等待合适的时机
Been waiting for the right moment.
来不来啊
You coming or what?
距引爆还有15分钟
15 minutes to detonation.
斯特兰奇
Strange.
Strange!
醒醒
Wake up.
斯特兰奇
Strange.
Strange!
A队C队去阿卡姆
Alpha and Charlie squads to Arkham.
B队D队去印第安山
Bravo and Delta to Indian Hill.
行动
Move!
企鹅  原来斯特兰奇先生
Hey, Penguin, so it turns out our Mr. Strange
是个大坏蛋呢
is a very bad man.
警察这就去抓他
The police are on to him now.
他们觉得他想逃  但他逃不掉的
They figure he's planning to run, but he won't.
这都多亏了我
Thanks to me.
谢谢你  芭芭拉
Thank you, Barbara.
你让我很满意
You have pleased me.
准备好  布奇
Saddle up, Butch,
我们得去抓个老朋友
we've got an old friend to catch.
醒醒  斯特兰奇
Wake up, Strange.
我知道你没死
I know you're in there.
醒醒
Wake up!
戈登
Oh, Gordon.
看来我的计划一定是出了岔子
I surmise my plan must have gone awry.
算是吧  我这就把你扶起来
You could say. I'm gonna stand you up now,
你带我去你的秘密实验室转转
and you're gonna give us a tour of your secret lab.
不
No.
你没的选
You don't have a choice.
是这边  对吧
It's this way, right?
不  我们不能过去  我设置了炸弹
No, we can't go down there. I set a bomb.
实验室要被炸毁了
The lab is going to blow up.
我们得赶紧跑
We have to get out of here!
10分钟后
In ten minutes,
0.25英里半径内的一切都将炸成渣
everything within a quarter mile radius will be dust.
简直疯了
That's madness.
如果你想活命
If you want to live--
反正我是想  那我们最好赶紧离开
which I do, frankly-- we had better leave.
我们在下面检测到了辐射性物质
We detected a radioactive material down there.
你把那些搬走了吧
You got it out first, right?
没时间了
There wasn't enough time.
他们逼我的
They forced my hand,
但我算过了
but I calculated
出现辐射云的概率很小
the chances of a radioactive cloud is fairly low.
如果你错了  就会死数千人
If you're wrong, thousands of people could die.
是啊
Yes, yes, yes,
但即便付出那样的代价
but paying that price will be better
也比把下面的怪物放出去要强
than releasing what's down there.
怎么关掉炸弹
How do we shut it down?
防护墙已经放下  实验室完全封锁了
The security walls are up. The lab is sealed.
肯定有办法进去的
There must be some way in.
我们得走了
We have to go!
我们得马上走了
We have to leave now!
告诉我怎么找到并拆除炸弹
Tell me how to get that bomb and shut it off
否则我这就打死你
or I'll batter you to death right here!
那么  年轻人
In which case, young man,
看来我只能去死了
I suppose I will just have to die.
等等  尼格玛知道怎么下去
Wait, Nygma knows a way down there.
帮帮忙
Could use some help.
嗯
Yeah.
你俩
You two,
你们有9分钟
you've got nine minutes.
-尽可能远离这里  -不行
- Get as far away from here as you can. - No.
快走
Go, go!
卢修斯  跟我来
Lucius, this way.
我当然知道怎么下去
Yes, of course, I know how,
但这么大惊小怪的是干什么
but what is with all the hoo-ha?
你们着什么急
What is the rush here?
赶紧的
Just do it.
这么做有我什么好处
What do I get if I do it?
你能活命
You get to live.
好吧
Fair enough.
安全系统解除
Security system is deactivated.
你会拆弹吗
You any good at defusing bombs?
我还不知道呢
I don't know yet.
你呢
You?
距引爆还有2分钟
Two minutes to detonation.
天呐
Oh, my.
有什么主意吗
Got any ideas?
有刀吗
You got a knife?
没有
No.
就绪
我们正赶往阿卡姆疏散病人
We're on a rush to Arkham for patient evacuation.
拆弹小队已经到场
We got bomb squad in set.
现在怎么办
What now?
你问我啊
You're asking me?
要不我们
How about if we just, uh,
把这些都拽掉吧
pull all this stuff off.
看看会怎么样
See what happens.
没有切断程序
There's no cutoff program, maybe,
或许也没有防拆弹的程序
maybe there's no tamper-proofing program.
嗯
Yeah.
不
No.
水
Water.
需要水
Need water.
水
Water.
怎么回事  人呢
What's going on? Hello?
45秒了
45 seconds.
15秒了
15 seconds.
拜托
Please.
我需要水
I need water.
水
Water.
我需要水
I need water.
人呢
Hello!
人呢  去哪了
Hello! Guys!
怎么回事啊
What's going on?
人呢
Hello!
我的人呢
Where are my people?
你不明白
Y-you don't understand.
得找到我的人
We have to find my people.
会有
There will be...
会有麻烦的
There will be consequences.
你个大英雄
You heroic son of a bitch.
核弹
A nuclear bomb, huh?
你绝对想不到我们怎么才来
You'll never guess what took us so long.
有麻烦
Problem.
不管下面之前有什么
Whatever was down there,
不管印第安山之前关了谁
whoever was down there at Indian Hill,
现在都跑出来了
they're not there anymore.
几个巡逻车在追击一辆
Couple of squad cars are in pursuit of a bus
离开了印第安山的大巴
that left the Indian Hills compound.
肯定是他们
That's got to be them.
绝不能让那辆大巴跑掉
That bus cannot get away.
这里是12队
This is Unit 12.
正在追击沿D线往南的阿卡姆大巴
In pursuit of Arkham bus heading south along the D Line.
12队  我在尤纳街
Calling you at Grand Unite Unit 12.
我们在下个街区拦截他们
We'll pick 'em up at the next block.
准备好
Get ready.
这里很窄
Don't have much space here.
前面有人  他跑不掉了
It's in civilian traffic ahead. He's blocked in.
在十字路口拦下他们
Block them at the cross street.
没看到  我再上前面看
Nothing. I'll check up ahead.
32号车呼叫布洛克警监  正往东去佩兹堡
Car 32 to Captain Bullock. Heading east toward Pettsburg.
该死
Damn, damn, damn.
大巴上有什么  吉姆
What's on that bus, Jim?
告诉我
Tell me what's on the bus?
怪物
Monsters.
不是吧  怪物
Come on. Monsters?
雨果·斯特兰奇宁可
Hugo Strange would rather
摧毁半个城市也不愿放走他们
destroy half the city than let them out.
现在他们被放跑了
And now they're out.
红色警戒
Code Red.
红色警戒  所有小队赶往佩兹堡高速
Code Red. All units Pettsburg Highway.
所有小队注意
All units be on the lookout
一辆佩兹堡高速上的印第安山大巴
for the Indian Hill bus on Pettsburg Highway.
布洛克警监  我看到大巴了
Captain Bullock, I've got eyes on the bus.
在南伯恩赛德高速下面
Under the South Burnside Expressway.
那就拦住他们啊
Well, then stop the damn thing.
别让它逃了
Don't let it get away.
到妈妈这儿来吧
Come to mama.
斯特兰奇教授
Professor Strange!
Professor Strange.
出来
Come out.
斯特兰奇  我们得谈谈
Strange. We need to talk.
你对我做了很坏的事
You did a very bad thing to me.
现在你要付出代价
And now you're going to pay.
不可能
Impossible.
没有什么
Nothing...
不可能
is impossible.
老天爷
Holy...
不
No.
如果我们不找到那辆大巴  哥谭就有大麻烦了
This city's in deep trouble if we don't find that bus.
我们去找到它吧
So let's find it.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
在这一带布20人的小队
I want squadrons of 20 in these quadrants here.
直升机空中搜索
I want choppers in the air,
战术小队去东区所有桥上
and I want tac units on all the East Side bridges.
布鲁斯
Bruce.
我得走了
I have to go.
我们可能有一阵要见不了了
I might not see you for a while,
但我会尽量保持联系
but I'll try to stay in touch.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我得去找到小莱
I have to find Lee.
做得对  伙计
Right move, mate.
帮个忙
Do me a favor.
替我跟布洛克道个别
Say good-bye to Bullock for me.
我不想经历凯尔特式的道别
I don't really want the whole Celtic farewell.
他要忙活好一阵了
He's gonna have his hands full,
但我觉得他能应付得来
but I think he can handle it.
好的
Will do.
巧克力
Chocolates.
姑娘喜欢巧克力
Girls like chocolates.
我会记住的
I'll keep that in mind.
这才是知道什么是最重要的
Well, there's a man who's got his priorities straight.
好女人的爱
The love of a good woman and all that.
那么
Well,
希望你吸取教训了  布鲁斯少爷
I hope you learned your lesson, Master Bruce.
你跟警方的冒险也会就此结束了吧
And that's the end of your adventures with the police, eh?
有个秘密议会  阿尔弗雷德
There's a secret council, Alfred.
一个掌管哥谭一切的秘密议会
A secret council that runs everything in Gotham.
老天爷
Oh, bloody hell.
是他们想要我死
It's them that wanted me dead.
我们很接近了  阿尔弗雷德
We're so close, Alfred,
就要发现终极真相了
we're so close to the ultimate truth.
见鬼
Oh, bloody hell.
别看我
Hey, don't look at me.
好吧
Right.
吉姆
Jim!
你去哪
Where you going?
我们还得去抓怪物呢
We got monsters to find.
你会抓到他们的  我得走了
And you'll find them. I have to go.
但城市有危险啊
But this city's in danger.
你能行的  我知道
You got this. I know you do.
我有更重要的事要做
And I have more important things to do.
-但是  -哈维
- But... - And Harvey,
怎么
Yeah?
你现在是老大了
You're the boss now.
剪个头吧
Maybe get a haircut?
那是我的车
That's my car.
That's-that's my car!
吉姆
Jim!
救命  救命
Help. Help.
可怜人
Oh, those poor souls.
有人吗
H-hello?
Hello?
谢谢
Thank you.